<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python Friends (Posts about automation)</title><link>/</link><description></description><atom:link href="/categories/automation.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2018 &lt;a href="mailto:python.friends.py@gmail.com"&gt;python-friends&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 18:41:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Auto-Scope</title><link>/posts/auto-scope/</link><dc:creator>Wytamma</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;
  At the last meeting, the group decided that python-friends should take a more hands-on project based turn. The nominate project is to build an open source whole slide scanner and automated cell discrimination and counting system. This project will involve many aspects of Python programming from controlling motors to building deep learning classifiers. We will work on this project at the weekly meetings. All are welcome to contribute, and no previous background is required.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Follow our progress on this blog.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Counting 80,000+ blood cells by hand will drive anyone to search for alternatives. A recent project I worked on involved looking for parasites in freshwater turtle blood cells (lots of turtle blood cells...).
  Due to the exotic nature of turtle cells, there are no readily available cell counting systems, and with the prospect of counting another 100,000+ cells I think we need to make one. Luckily we have &lt;a href="https://xkcd.com/353/"&gt;Python super powers&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The first part of the project involves designing motor mounts to control the stage and focus. I'm going to work on this over the weekend, and hopefully, we'll have a system to start prototyping code on Monday.
&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>auto-scope</category><category>automation</category><guid>/posts/auto-scope/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>